garyjwolff.com 2019-01-13

# Privacy Policy for garyjwolff.com

[Home](https://www.garyjwolff.com/index.html): Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy for  
www.garyjwolff.com

I HATE legal stuff, but in order to use Google Adsense and other affiliate marketing programs on this website, I needed a Privacy Policy. So here is my best attempt at being a good citizen.  

Having been spammed virtually millions of times since I started doing email in 1995, perhaps more than anyone else, I can fully appreciate the importance of protecting people's privacy. 

This document outlines the types of personal information collected when you use this site, as well as some of the steps taken to safeguard that information. I hope this will help you make an informed decision about sharing personal information. 

I give you my [Scout's honor](http://garywolff.com/eagle.html) to maintain the highest standards of decency, fairness, and integrity on this website. Likewise, I am committed to protecting customers', consumers' and online visitors' privacy to the greatest extent possible.

### Personal Information

Personally identifiable information is only collected from the visitors to this website on a voluntary basis. That may include for example, name, postal address, email address, company name, or telephone number, when ordering products or services.

This kind of information may also be collected if you request information, participate in a contest or sweepstakes, sign up to join my email list, or request some other service or information. The information collected is internally reviewed, used to improve the content of the website, notify visitors of updates, and respond to visitor inquiries.

Once information is reviewed, it is either discarded or stored in my files, for my eyes only. If I make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information, I will inform you by placing a notice on this site. Personal information received from any visitor will be used only for internal purposes and will never, ever be sold or provided to third parties.

### Use of Cookies

Cookies may be used to help personalize your online experience. Cookies are identifiers that are routinely transferred by virtually every website these days to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable website systems to recognize your browser. 

The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize the site's pages, or register with any of the site's services, a cookie simply enables a website to recall your specific information on subsequent visits.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying your Web browser; however, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the full, interactive features of the site.

### Use of Web Beacons

A web beacon is a transparent image file used to monitor your journey around a single website or collection of sites. They are commonly used by sites that hire third-party services to monitor traffic. They may be used in association with cookies to understand how visitors interact with the pages and content on the pages of a web site.

It is possible I may choose in the future to use third-party advertisements that use cookies and web beacons in the course of ads being served on this web site to ascertain how many times you've seen an advertisement. No personally identifiable information you give is provided to them for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information on this web site.

Some third-party advertisements may be provided by Google, which uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google uses the DART cookie, which enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visits to this site and other sites on the Web. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is being sent. Privacy software can be used to override web beacons. Taking either of these actions shouldn't cause a problem with this site, should you so choose.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

This website is directed to adults; it is not directed to children under the age of 13. This site is operated in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, and I will not knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under 13 years of age.

### Release of Information

If this website is sold, the information obtained from you through your voluntary participation in this site may transfer to the new owner as a part of the sale in order that the service being provided to you may continue. In that event, you will receive notice through this website of that change in control and practices, and reasonable efforts will be made to ensure that the purchaser honors any opt-out requests you might make.

### How You Can Correct or Remove Information

This privacy policy is provided as a statement to you of my commitment to protect your personal information. If you have submitted personal information through this website and would like that information deleted from my records or would like to update or correct that information, please use my [Contact Me](https://www.garyjwolff.com/contact-me-form.html) page.

### Google Search Box

The search box on this web site is powered by Google Inc. You acknowledge and agree that [Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy.html) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box, you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy.

### Updates and Effective Date

It is possible that changes may be needed to this policy in the future. If there is a material change in the privacy practices, I will indicate on this site that the privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the new privacy policy. I encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will know what information is collected and how it is used.

### Agreeing to Terms

If you cannot agree to this Privacy Policy as posted here on this website, I would request that you please do not use this site or any services offered here.

Your use of this site indicates acceptance of this privacy policy.  Thanks so much for reading and for your kind understanding. How did I do?  

Cheers,  
Gary

[Aug. 23, 2014 update: Yesterday I finally got around to updating my Google Analytics tracking code to the new-generation, required Universal tracking code, which is an amazing tool that provides site owners more detailed data on the demographics (e.g. age, gender, location) and interests of their site visitors. 

In the process, I'll now have a much better feel for the kind of content my visitors are looking for, and enable me to attract the kinds of advertising that meets the desires of my audience. 

You should know, however, that under no circumstances is any personally-identifiable information collected through any Google advertising product or feature that is tied to data gathered from advertising cookies. 

Of course, site visitors can always opt-out of the Google Analytics advertising features by adjusting their browser ad settings, or by using the [NAI's consumer opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) from interest-based advertising or Google Analytics' [currently available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) for the web.]
